Georgia Sfakianaki

⊠ gsfakian@uni-bremen.de • 🕆 gsfakianaki.github.io • 🐚 gsfakianaki Nationality: Greek • Date of Birth: 05 March 1991

Personal statement

I am a Ph.D. candidate in Industrial Mathematics with expertise in inverse problems, experienced both in theoretical and computational approaches. I am self-motivated and focused on teamwork with excellent communication and organizational skills. My character is defined by analytical thinking and a problem-solving attitude which enable me to always overcome obstacles.

Work experience

Graduate Research Assistant

Institute of Applied and Computational Mathematics, FO.R.T.H. Study of existing scientific software for eventual application to concrete problems in the field of vascular biomechanics.

Student Internship

Institute of Applied and Computational Mathematics, FO.R.T.H. Theoretical study and implementation of the Kalman Filter for data processing.

Hellenic Statistical Authority Conducted interviews with residents in designated areas while adhering to specific guidelines and confidentiality laws.

Census Taker

Education

Ph.D. in Industrial Mathematics

Research Training Group π^3 , University of Bremen

Thesis: "On the connection between sparsity and tolerances in parameter and data space"

Supervisor: Dr. Iwona Piotrowska-Kurczewski

M.Sc. in Applied and Computational Mathematics, (Very Good, B+)

Department of Mathematics and Applied Mathematics, University of Crete

Major in Scientific Computing

Thesis: "Data Assimilation Methods" Supervisor: Prof. Michael Plexousakis

B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics, (Very Good, 7.3/10)

Department of Applied Mathematics, University of Crete Major in Mathematical Methods and Software Development

Thesis: "Principal Component Analysis" Supervisor: Prof. Michael Plexousakis

Teaching experience

- Programming in Python (undergraduate course, tutoring in Greek)
- Theory of linear inverse problems (graduate course, tutoring in English)

Research interests

o Inverse problems, Tikhonov regularization, scientific computing, data assimilation methods

Heraklion, Greece Jan 2015 - Jun 2015

Heraklion, Greece

Jul 2014 - Sep 2014

Chania, Greece

May 2011

Bremen, Germany

since Nov 2016

Heraklion, Greece

Sep 2014 - Jun 2016

Heraklion, Greece

Sep 2008 - Nov 2014

Languages

- Greek
- English

Advanced level - IELTS Band Score 7.5 (2016)

Technical skills

- \circ $\bf Programming:$ experienced in Matlab, Python, basic knowledge of C and Java
- o Scientific tools: basic knowledge of LifeV, SimVascular, ANSA, Gmsh and ParaView
- Typesetting: experienced in LATEX, good knowledge of MS Office and Libre Office
- Operating Systems: experienced both in Unix-based and Windows environments

Workshops

- o navigare Carrer Coaching for International Women in Science 2017/2018
- o Good scientific practice for (Post) Doctoral Researchers
- Soft-skills workshop "Getting Started" for PhD students, Scientific writing, Gender and intercultural training course

Hobbies

• Watercolor painting